Henry DeWolf Smyth Papers 1885-1987 Mss.Ms.Coll.15
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Professional Correspondence, 1916-86
  - Briggs, Lyman J.
    - Smith, Lloyd P.
    - see also Conant, James B.
    - see also Ser. V, Envelope 1 - Briggs, Lyman J.
    NDRC; uranium project
    - Folder #1, 1941
    - Folder #2, 1942-46
      OSRD list of reports, 1941-42
  - Brinner, H. A.
  - Brobeck, Wayne P., 1955; 1956; 1961
  - Brobeck, William M.
    - see Joint Committee on Atomic Energy
  - Brode, Bernice, 1953
  - Brode, Robert B., 1947-59
    cosmic ray project; International Union
  - Brode, Wallace R., 1958-59
  - Brolley, John E., 1971
  - Bronk, Detlev W., 1947-57
  - Brooke, Z. N.
    - see University of Cambridge
  - Brookes, William J.
  - Brookfield, H. M., 1953
  - Brookhaven National Laboratory, 1955; 1961
  - Brookings Institution. The, 1962
    - Lansdown, Brenda
  - Brooks, Harvey, 1959
    Oak Ridge/breeder situation
  - Brooks, Kennedy C.
  - Brooks, Paul, 1954
    - see also Houghton Mifflin Company
  - Brooks, Van Wyck
  - Brown, Alfred Seely, 1945
  - Brown, Barrett, 1953
  - Brown, Francis
  - Brown, G. Edwin, Jr., 1962
    - see also Atomic Industrial Forum, Inc.
    - see also Ser. III, Idaho SL-1 Reactor Accident
  - Brown, H. S.
    - see Tolman, Richard C.
  - Brown, Howard C., Jr., 1961-68
    - Seaborg, Glenn T.
    - see also Hall, John A.
    - see also Reichardt, Charles H.
  - Brown, J. Douglas
    - Elgin, J. C.
    - Goheen, Robert F.
    - Howell, Samuel C.
    - Perkins, C. D.
    - Summerfield, Martin
    - Test, A. L.
    - see also Berg, Samuel
    - see also Seamans, Robert C., Jr.
    - see also Shubik, Martin
    Princeton
    - Folder #1, 1949-59
    - Folder #2, 1960-62
    - Folder #3, 1963-65
    - Folder #4, 1966
  - Brown, J. Moreau
  - Brown, John, 1955
  - Brown, Keirn C.
  - Brown, M. E.
    - see Gale Research Company
  - Brown, Stuart Gerry
    - see Syracuse University
  - Brown, T. Wistar
    - see Joseph Henry Center
  - Browne, Harry L., 1952
  - Brownell, F. H., 1950; 1951
  - Brownson, Helen L., 1958
  - Broyles, Arthur A.
  - Brynielsson, Harry, 1952
  - Buchan, Alastair
    - see Eklund, Sigvard
  - Buchanan, John G., 1964
  - Buchanan, Robert K.
  - Buchta, J. W., 1944-63
    - see also Bradbury, Norris E.
    - see also Dodds, Harold W.
    - see also Winckler, John R.
    HDS editing for "Physical Review"
  - Buck, [?]
  - Buckley, Oliver
    - see Waterman, Alan T.
  - Buckley, S. W.
    - see Salisbury, Morse
  - Budd, Edward G., Jr., 1959
  - Buddington, A. F.
  - Buell, William A., 1952
  - Buetow, H. P.
  - Buffalo, Harvey A.
    - see International Union of Pure and Applied Physics
  - Buggs, Benjamin
    - see Buggs, [Katie]
  - Buggs, [Katie], 1959
    - Buggs, Benjamin
  - Bugher, John C.
    - see Hall, John A.
    - see Kaplan, Joseph
  - Bukantz, Samuel C., 1954
  - Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists
    - Adams, Ruth S.
    - Allison, Helen C.
    - Bellow, Susan
    - Lewis, Richard S.
    - Rabinowitch, Eugene
    - Shils, Edward A.
    - Simpson, John
    - Smith, Alice Kimball (Mrs. Cyril)
    - Swanson, Edgar
    - Folder #1, 1951-53; 1956
    - Folder #2, 1957-61
  - Bundy, McGeorge
  - Bunting, Mary I.
    - see Coyle, Dan D.
  - Burch, Alan F.
    - see Rabi, I. I.
  - Burchard, John E., 1941-44
    - Mayo, George
    NDRC rent pd. to Princeton
  - Burden, William, 1964
  - Burford, W. B., III
  - Burger, Ralph W., 1962
  - Burke, Edward J., 1963
  - Burke, J. E.
    - see Johnson, Warren C.
  - Burleigh, Nathaniel G.
    - see Faris, Marvin L.
  - Burnett, Whit, 1954
  - Burnham, George H., 1944
    - Mulliken, Robert S.
  - Burns, John H., 1970
  - Burrell, G. A.
    - see Manning, Van H.
  - Burrill, C. M.
  - Burt, John, 1956-57
    - DeLong, Edmund S.
  - Burt, Struthers, 1946
  - Burton, Harry
  - Burton, Milton
    - see Ser. II, Mulliken Committee
  - Bush, Alfred L., 1969
  - Bush, Robert R.
  - Bush, Vannevar, 1940-52; n.d.
    - Clay, Lucius D.
    - DuBridge, Lee A.
    - Thorpe, Willard
    NDRC/OSRD; uranium project
  - Busse, Paul, 1946-55; days; n.d.
    - Bowen, H. G.
    - Mestres, Ricardo A.
    OSRD; Edison Foundation
  - Butler, Carol, 1964
  - Butler, E. G.
  - Butler, Geoffrey
  - Butterworth, [?], 1958
    - Kohnstamm, Max
    Euratom
  - Byrnes, James F. (Box Series I: 7)
  - Cabot, Henry B.
  - Cagle, Fred R.
  - Cahnmann, H. J.
  - Cairns, S. S.
    - see Ser. VIA, Stockpiling and rationing of scientific manpower. The
  - Calingaert, George, 1942
    - see also Hess, Lewis
    hexacarbonyls
  - Cameron, Brodnax, 1947-57
    - Heermance, Radcliffe
  - Camp, E. Q.
  - Campbell, C. I., 1950
  - Campbell, Glenn, 1954
  - Campbell, Joseph
    - see Zuckert, Eugene M.
  - Campbell, W. Glenn
    - see American Enterprise Association
  - Campbell, Walker E.
    - see Boyer, Marion Willard
  - Canaday, Ward M.
  - Canham, Erwin D., 1960
  - Cannan, Hildegard Wilson, 1954
  - Cannan, R. Keith
    - see Ser. II, Associated Universities, Inc.
  - Cannon, Jo Anne, 1949
  - Cantril, Hadley, 1945
  - Cantril, S. T., 1942
    potential hazards at Palmer Lab
  - Cargo, William I.
    - Cleveland, Harlan
    - Czayo, George M.
    - Kratzer, Myron B.
    - Sisco, Joseph J.
    - Stanger, Ernest L.
    - Wells, Algie A.
    - see also Cole, W. Sterling
    - see also Eklund, Sigvard
    - see also Stanger, Ernest L.
    - see also Wells, Algie A.
    IAEA
    - Folder #1, 1961
    - Folder #2, 1962-63
  - Carll, [?], 1955-56
  - Carll, M. L.
    - see Babcock, W. R.
  - Carlson, William, 1957
  - Carmichael, Leonard
    - see Smithsonian Institution
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace
    - Finkelstein, Lawrence S.
    - Johnson, Joseph E.
    - Platig, E. Raymond
    - Riefler, Winfield W.
    - Shotwell, James T.
    Committee on Atomic Energy; reports
    - Folder #1, 1945-46
    - Folder #2, 1963-64
  - Carothers, Neil J., 1954
  - Carothers, S., 1963
  - Carpenter, Donald F., 1949
  - Carr, James K., 1963
  - Carr, John W., III, 1962
  - Carriel, Cruse, 1945
    Smyth Report corrections
  - Carrier, Oliver, Jr., 1956
  - Carroll, H. F., 1954-57
  - Carter, David Southard, 1950
  - Carter, E. Finley, 1957
  - Carter, Edward C., II, 1986
    Smyth Papers at APS
  - Carver, Lloyd Allen, 1951
  - Carver, T. R.
  - Case Institute of Technology, 1953
  - Case, Clifford P., 1956-70
  - Case, Everett N., 1977
  - Casey, Clifford H., 1948
  - Casper, Barry, 1953
  - Cassels, Louis, 1956
    HDS comments on AEC Commissioner Murray
  - Cassese, S., 1949
    - Gorman, Arthur E.
    - Hafstad, Lawrence A.
  - Castle, Emery N.
    - see Glennan, T. Keith
    - see Ser. IV, History of the IAEA
  - Castle, H.
    - see Ser. V, Envelope 1a - Castle, H.
  - Catholic Council of Electrical Workers, 1954
    - Morgan, Henry S.
  - Cattell, Jaques
    - see American Men of Science
  - Centennial Review of Arts and Sciences, 1956
    - Millar, Branford P.
  - Cernuschi, Felix, 1945
  - Chadwick, [?], n.d.
    Smyth Report comments w/HDS marginalia
  - Chakravarti, M. N.
    - see Ser. IV, Tarapur Project
  - Challener, Richard D.
    - see Ser. II, Princeton University. [Memorial...]
  - Chalon, Jean R., 1946
  - Chamberlain, W. E., 1956
  - Chambers, Louise, 1960
  - Champlain, W. P.
    - see Reynolds, George T.
  - Chandler, G.
    - see LADSIRLAC
  - Chandler, Lester V., 1959
    - Bogdonoff, Seymour M.
    - Reynolds, George T.
    U.R.A.
  - Chaney, Ralph W., 1953
    - Dorf, Erling
  - Chapman, Sydney, 1946
    comments on Smyth Report
  - Charnoff, Gerald, 1962
  - Charyk, Joseph V.
    - see Jet Propulsion Publications Program
  - Chase, Aurin M.
  - Chase, R. R., 1957-58
    IBM 610 at Princeton
  - Chemical and Engineering News, 1948-52
    - Murphy, Walter J.
    - Parkinson, N. A.
  - Cheng, Victor, 1965; 1968
  - Cherwell, [?]
    - see Ser. III, England, Brussels & Paris...
  - Chesterman, Francis J.
    - see Massachusetts Institute of Technology. Dept. of Physics
  - Chicago Sun-Times, 1955
  - Chilton, Thomas H., 1968
  - Chisholm, Raymond S., 1946
    extraction of fission products from oxide
  - Chow, T. C., 1947
    sciences in China
  - Christ, Carl F., 1954
  - Christeller, Norman L.
    - see Institute for Defense Analyses
  - Christman, A. B., 1967
    Oppenheimer case; MdeCS diaries
  - Christofferson, L. G., 1959
  - Church, Eugene L.
  - Cincinnati Gas & Electric Company, 1952
    - McClure, R. B.
  - Cisler, Walker L., 1959-70
    - see also Fund for Peaceful Atomic Development, Inc.
  - Clague, Ewan
  - Clark, Duncan, 1955
  - Clark, Francis G., 1970
  - Clark, G. L., 1954
  - Clark, Grenville, 1958-66
    - see also Ser. II, Dublin (N.H.) Conference
  - Clark, J. C., 1957
  - Clark, J. McAdam, 1964-68
    U.S./British agreement on Civil Uses of Atomic Energy
  - Clark, Jacqueline
    - see Harcourt, Brace and Company, Inc.
  - Clark, R. E.
  - Clark, Robert L.
    - see Ser. III, Scientific manpower
  - Clautice, William E., 1946
  - Clay, George, 1962
  - Clay, George R., 1962
  - Clay, Lucius D.
    - see Bush, Vannevar
  - Clayton, W. L., 1947
  - Clemen, Rudolf, 1963
  - Clendenin, W. W.
  - Cleveland, Harlan, 1961-65; n.d.
    - Jones, [?]
    - Wallner, [?]
    - see also Cargo, William I.
    - see also Hefner, Frank K.
    - see also Reporter. The
    - see also Rusk, Dean
    - see also Simsarian, James
    - see also Sisco, Joseph J.
    - see also Trapnell, Edward R.
    IAEA; HDS on Board of Gov.; safeguards
  - Cleveland, Richard F., 1958
    - Weigle, Richard D.
  - Clifford, William, 1954
  - Cloud, Dudley
    - see Ser. VIII, Stopping the atomic...
  - Coale, Ansley J.
    - see Ser. II, Social Science Research Council
  - Cockcroft, John (Sir), 1951-53
    - see also Ser. III, England, Brussels & Paris...
  - Coe, J. R., n.d.
  - Coe, Roger J.
  - Coghill, John (W. H.)
  - Cogill, John
    - see Seitz, Frederick
  - Coheen, Meyer
  - Cohen, Hennig
    - see Russell, Donald
  - Cohen, I. Bernard, 1950
    HDS teaching at Harvard
  - Cohen, Karl, 1942-44
    - Thompson, W. I.
    Columbia reports: post war research on atomic power & centrifuge program
  - Cohen, Leon W., 1956-57
  - Cohen, Martin J.
  - Cohen, V. W.
  - Cohn, Byron E., 1949-61
  - Cohn, Victor, 1951
  - Cohn, Waldo E., 1952
    - Sapirie, S. R.
    - Weaver, Warren
    - see also Sapirie, S. R.
    re: Cohn's security clearance
  - Coiner, Richard T., 1950
    - see also Teller, Edward
  - Colbert, Joan H., 1970 (Box Series I: 8)
  - Colby, Elbridge, 1962
  - Colby, Martha
    - see Colby, Walter F.
  - Colby, Walter F., 1950-51
    - Colby, Martha
    - Glasheen, George L.
    - see also Pohl, R. W.
  - Cole, W. Sterling, 1954-61
    - Cargo, William I.
    - see also Dean, Gordon
    - see also Spitzer, Lyman, Jr.
    - see also Ser. III, Russian atomic explosions
    H-bomb; Oppenheimer case; Strauss; IAEA Warsaw Conf.
  - Cole, William H., 1957
  - Colebrook, Mulford, 1964
  - Colegrove, Kenneth
    - see American Political Science Association
  - Coleman, Earl E.
    - see Ser. VIII, "The `Smyth Report' "
  - Coleman, John S.
    - see National Academy of Sciences
  - Colley, Allen F.
  - Collier, D. W., 1957
  - Collins, F. L.
    - see Ser. II, Princeton University. Appointments
  - Collins, George B., 1952-57
    Brookhaven Cosmotron
  - Colman, J. S.
  - Colonial Trust Company, 1956
  - Comar, Cyril L.
  - Commission to Study the Organization of Peace, 1945-49
    - Eichelberger, Clark M.
    - Olson, Margaret
    reports on: atomic weapons control, peace treaties, UN guards
  - Compton, Arthur H.
    - Bush, Vannevar
    - Frankel, A.
    - Groves, Leslie R.
    - Sibley, Alden
    - see also Alexander, P. P.
    - see also Echols, L. S., Jr.
    - see also Hogness, T. R.
    - see also Lilienthal, David E.
    - see also Rabinowitch, E.
    - see also Roosevelt, Franklin D.
    - see also Ser. II, Uranium Data & Reports
    - see also Ser. V, Envelope 1 - Fermi, Enrico
    - see also Ser. V, Envelope 1 - Pegram, George B.
    OSRD projects at Princeton & Univ. of Chicago
    - Folder #1, 1941-43
      deuterium; Princeton separation & cyclotron projects; heavy water; tuballoy; Westinghouse
    - Folder #2, 1944
      metallurgical project; magnetic purification process
    - Folder #3, 1945-56
      Wigner's return to Princeton
  - Compton, E. R.
  - Compton, Karl Taylor, 1940-54
    - see also Forsythe, W. E.
    - see also West, Andrew F.
    - see also Ser. VIII, Effect of fluorescence...
    - see also Ser. VIII, Radiating potentials...
    re: NDRC; staffing defense projects
  - Compton, Randolph P., 1966
  - Conant, James B.
    - Briggs, Lyman J.
    - Schechter, Ben
    - Wilson, E. Bright, Jr.
    - see also Ser. II, Johnson and May Bills...
    re: NDRC/OSRD projects, budgets
    - Folder #1, 1941-43
    - Folder #2, 1944-47; 1957
      re: Smyth Report, secrecy
  - Conant, Melvin
  - Condit, Kenneth H., 1945
  - Condit, Richard, 1947
  - Condon, Edward U., 1942-74
    - Olsen, Elvin E.
    - see also Bailey, Herbert S., Jr.
    - see also Smith, Datus C., Jr.
    Smyth Report, Condon hearing
  - Cone, Ed
  - Congress of Industrial Organizations, 1953
    - Knight, O. A.
  - Conkie, W. R., 1956
  - Connor, Henry W., 1956
  - Conover, John C.
  - Conover, Julian D.
    - see Ser. II, American Mining Congress, Denver, Colorado
  - Conrad, R. D.
  - Consodine, William A., 1945; 1949
    - Alexander, P. P.
    - see also Lawrence, Ernest O.
    - see also Ser. V, Envelope 1b - Lawrence, E. O.
    Smyth Report
  - Conway, John T., 1961; 1965
    - see also Ser. III, Joint Committee on Atomic Energy
    - see also Ser. IV, General and safeguards
  - Conway, Rose A., 1945
  - Cook, Clinton S., 1953
    - Wallace, C. K.
  - Cook, Earl, 1955
  - Cook, Earnshaw, 1951
    aeronautic nuclear propulsion
  - Cook, Frederick A., 1966
  - Cook, George R., 3rd, 1961; 1966
  - Cook, R. W., 1949-57
    - see also Ser. III, Savannah River Project
    Oak Ridge organizational charts
  - Cooksey, Donald, 1950-51
  - Cool, Rod L., 1966
    - see also Ser. II, High Energy Physics Policy Statements
  - Cooley, Richard A., 1960
  - Coomes, E. A.
  - Cooper, A., 1953
  - Cooper, C. M.
  - Cooper, Charles M.
  - Cooper, John C., 1958
  - Cooper, Lewis C., 1960
    - Aubin, E. G., Jr.
  - Cope, Arthur C., 1954
  - Copley, C. J., 1956
  - Coquelin, William J., n.d.
  - Cork, Bruce
    - see Ser. II, High Energy Physics Policy Statements
  - Cornell, S. D., 1957
  - Cornog, R., 1942
    - Cowie, Dean
    - see also Hess, [?]
  - Cornog, Robert
  - Corrosion Chemical Company, 1954
    - Jury, J. T.
  - Cortada, James N., 1965
  - Coryell, Charles D., 1945-63
    - Donnelly, Warren H.
    - English, Spofford G.
    - Fidler, H. A.
    - Friedman, Abraham
    - Henson, E. T.
    - Hickenlooper, Bourke B.
    - O'Donnell, Ashton J.
    - Pfeiffer, John
    - Playfair, W. E.
    - Rolander, C. A., Jr.
    - Russell, Richard B.
    re: secrecy, Russian A-Bomb
  - Cosmos Club, 1985-86 (Box Series I: 9)
    - Brady, Edward L.
    - Goff, James F.
    - Meyers, Tedson J.
  - Cosmos Club. Admissions, 1950-85
  - Council on Foreign Relations
    - Altschul, Frank
    - Berkner, Lloyd V.
    - Brennan, Lorna
    - Conant, Melvin
    - Davis, John W.
    - Davison, W. Phillips
    - Diez, William Edwin
    - Jessup, Philip C.
    - Kintner, William R.
    - Kissinger, Henry A.
    - Lindsay, Franklin A.
    - Mallory, Walter H.
    - Folder #1, 1945-54
    - Folder #2, 1955-58
    - Folder #3, 1963-64
  - Couper, R. W., 1966
  - Courter, Jim, 1986
    re: nuclear weapons testing
  - Cousins, Norman, 1945-58
  - Cover, John H., 1950; 1955
    - see also Institute on World Organization
  - Cowenhoven, Margaret R., 1959; 1966
  - Cowie, Dean, 1942
    - see also Cornog, R.
  - Cox, Kenneth A., 1959
    re: Strauss nomination as Sec'y of Commerce
  - Coyle, Dan D., 1954-64
    - Bunting, Mary I.
    - Johnson, Wesley M.
    - Vogt, Roy S.
    - see also Jauho, [Pelda?]
    - see also Ser. II, Joseph Henry House
  - Craig, Clyde G.
  - Crane, Edward M., 1923; 1959
  - Cranston, Alan
  - Crawford, Everett L., 1957
  - Crawford, Frederick C., 1951
  - Creese, James, 1946-52
  - Creighton, William J., 1952
    - Atlanta Architect-Engineer Associates
  - Crenesse, Pierre
    - see Lilienthal, David E.
  - Crenshaw, J. L., 1945
  - Creutz, Edward C., 1941-62
    - McReynolds, A. W.
    - Miller, Park, Jr.
    Metallurgical Lab.
  - Creveling, K. H., 1957
  - Crew, William H., 1952
  - Crewe, Albert, 1967
  - Crist, R. H., 1943; 1945
    separation data
  - Critchfield, Charles L., 1951
    - see also Strom, Ralph J.
  - Crockett, William J., 1963-65
    - [Johnson, Lyndon B.]
    - see also Lewis, Verne B.
  - Cromelin, John, 1946
  - Cromwell, Jarvis, 1946-65
  - Cross, Richard
  - Crouch, Kenneth E.
  - Crow, Ralph L.
  - Crowe, Thomas J., 1969
  - Crowsen, Delmar L., 1968
    - see also Ser. IV, Nonproliferation Treaty
  - Cruikshank, C. G., 1943-44
    OSRD
  - Cudhea, David W., 1955
  - Cudlipp, Chandler, [1956?]
  - Culling, John H., 1946
  - Cultural and Scientific Conference for World Peace, 1949
    - Dorner, Hanna
  - Cummerford, John
    - see Harrington, Charles D.
  - Cummins, J. E., 1959
  - Cuninggim, Merrimon
  - Cunningham, Francis, 1961
  - Cunningham, W. C., 1945
  - Currie, L. M., 1961
  - Curtis, H. J.
  - Curtis, Harry A.
  - Cushman, Robert E.
  - Cusick, Paul V.
  - Cutler, Robert, 1954
  - Czayo, George M., 1961
    - see also Hipsley, Elmer R.
  - Dalzell, R. Carson, 1966 (Box Series I: 10)
  - Daniels, Farrington, 1956
  - Danielson, G. C.
  - Darby, Hugh Hackland, 1956
  - Darrow, Karl K., 1952-67
    re: Am. Phys. Soc.
  - Darrow, Whitney
    - see Smith, Datus C., Jr.
  - Das Gupta, A., 1962
  - Davidson, J. G., 1955
  - Davidson, W. L., Jr., 1945
  - Davidson, Ward F., 1946
    Edison Electric
  - Davies, J. W., 1959
  - Davies, John D., 1957-59
    Princeton Alumni Weekly
  - Davies, Richard L., 1949
  - Davis, C. B.
  - Davis, Dan B.
    - see Ser. II, Applied Science Corporation of Princeton (ASCOP)
  - Davis, J. H., 1967
  - Davis, John W.
  - Davis, Joseph A.
  - Davis, Mary [W?] iggins (Mrs. Platt W.), 1949
    Freistadt case
  - Davis, Nathaniel P., 1954-55
  - Davis, Raymond F., 1947
  - Davis, Regula
    - see Physics Today
  - Davis, Robert R.
  - Davis, Shelby Cullom, 1945; 1948
  - Davis, W. Kenneth, 1955-72
    - Benjamin, Robert S.
    - see also Atomic Energy Comm. HDS Consultant to
  - Davis, Watson, 1945; 1947
    - see also Ser. VIA, Westinghouse 10th annual science talent search banquet
  - Davison, W. C., 1961
  - Davison, W. Phillips
    - see Ser. II, Council on Foreign Relations. Science...
  - Davisson, C. J.
    - see Ser. IX, Tuve, Merle A.
  - Dawson, Donald S., 1949
    - Truman, Harry S.
    AEC acceptance
  - Day, Melvin S.
  - Dean, Evelyn L., 1949
  - Dean, Gordon, 1950-56
    - Cole, W. Sterling
    - Lilienthal, David E.
    - Morrill, James L.
    - Sproul, R. G.
    - see also Berkner, Lloyd V.
    - see also Borst, Lyle
    - see also Cohn, Waldo E.
    - see also Congress of Industrial Organizations
    - see also Long, Anne
    - see also Smith, Robert J.
    - see also Thomas, Charles Allen
    - see also Truman, Harry S.
    - see also Wherry, Kenneth S.
    - see also Ser. II, American Mining Congress, Denver, Colorado
    - see also Ser. II, Council on Foreign Relations. Nuclear...
    - see also Ser. II, H-Bomb
    AEC
  - de Angelis, M. L., 1958
  - De Benedetti, Sergio, 1951
  - De Bruin, Richard W., 1959
  - DeCarlo, Charles
  - Dechert, Robert, 1964
  - Decker, Stan D., 1947
  - Dees, Sarah
  - de Hemptinne, [?]
    - see Robiliart, H.
  - Dehlinger, Walter H., 1924
  - de Kay, Drake
    - see Encyclopedia Americana
  - Delano, James K.
  - DeLong, Edmund S., 1955-59
    - see also Burt, John
    biog. sketch
  - del Rosario, Leticia, 1951-52
  - Delsasso, Lewis A., 1940-43
    Aberdeen Proving Ground
  - de Mautort, R., 1959
  - De Ment, Jack, 1945
  - Dempster, A. J., 1924
  - Denker, David D., 1960; 1965
  - De Palma, Samuel, 1969-72
    - Jacques, Philippe G.
    - Mace, Howard P.
    - see also McDonald, John W.
  - DeRenzis, Enzi
  - Derieux, James C., 1954
  - Derry, John A.
  - Deutch, John M.
  - Devers, Jacob L.
  - Devons, S[amuel]
  - De Vore, Charles, 1965
  - DeWald, Ernest T., 1956
  - DeWolfe, Genie Griffin
  - Dexter, F. D.
  - Dick, Bob
  - Dicke, R. H., 1960
    - Markham, Jesse
    - Maxwell, Bryce
  - Dickinson, William C.
  - Dicksen, John
    - see National Cyclopedia of American Biography
  - Dickson, Cecil B.
  - Dickson, John, 1951
    biog. info.
  - Dienes, G. J., 1957
    - see also Morse, Philip M.
  - Dietrich, Charles W., 1952
  - Diez, William Edwin
  - DiGiovanni, H. J., 1957
  - Dignan, Thomas S.
  - Dillinger, J. R., 1957
  - Dillon, J. H., 1960
  - Dinsmore, R. Braddock, 1952-66
  - Dirac, Paul
  - Disque, R. C., 1948
  - Dix, Howard W., 1941; 1949
    - see also Bradford, E. B.
  - Dix, William S., 1961-68
    - see also Ser. II, Journals, Sale of
    re: disposition of HDS papers
  - Doan, R. L., 1942-50; 1963
  - Doar, John M., 1975
  - Dodds, Harold W.
    - Adams, Arthur
    - Barnard, Chester I.
    - Bowles, Frank H.
    - Chandler, Lester V.
    - Earl, Elliott
    - Gemmell, Edgar M.
    - Landon, S. Whitney
    - Sachs, Alexander
    - Stearns, Robert L.
    - see also Barker, Joseph W.
    - see also Compton, Karl Taylor
    - see also Kendall, E. C.
    - see also Pike, Sumner T.
    - see also Stearns, J. C.
    - see also Young, Raymond J.
    re: Princeton Univ. administration
    - Folder #1, 1938-54
    - Folder #2, 1955
    - Folder #3, 1955
    - Folder #4, 1956
      policy re: research funding
    - Folder #5, 1956-57
    - Folder #6, 1959-68
  - Dodge, David S., 1986
    Bohm case
  - Dodwell, H. W., 1964-65
  - Dombras, Theodore T.
    - see Robertson, Howard P.
  - Donaldson, Coleman duP., 1955-57
  - Donnel, Alton P., n.d.
  - Donnelly, Warren H., 1960
    - see also Coryell, Charles D.
  - Donovan, James B.
    - see Brakeley, George A.
  - Donovan, William J.
  - do Prado, Luiz Cintra, 1968
  - Dorf, Erling
    - see Chaney, Ralph W.
    - see Nassau Club
  - Dorman, Stuart
    - see McGraw-Hill Book Company, Inc.
  - Dorner, Hanna
    - see Cultural and Scientific Conference for World Peace
  - Doskocil, Albert C.
  - Doty, Paul M.
  - Doub, George Cochran, 1957
  - Doubleday & Company, Inc., 1958
    - Winslow, Richard K.
  - Douglas, Louis H.
  - Douglas, William O., 1974
    re: JRO
  - Dow Chemical Company, 1954
  - Downer, Alan
  - Drake, Francis J., Jr.
  - Drake, Robert M., Jr., 1957; 1963
    - see also Jet Propulsion Research Program
    - see also Princeton University. Scien. Research & Higgins Fund Comm.
  - Draley, J. E.
  - Dryden, Hugh L., 1956
  - DuBridge, Lee A., 1940-69
    - see also Oppenheimer, J. Robert
    - see also Ser. II, Johnson and May Bills.
    - see also Ser. III, Thermonuclear weapons...
    - see also Ser. VIA, Turner, Lou. Remarks at memorial service
  - Duer, M. V. B., 1945; 1975
    alleged HDS article
  - Duffendack, O. S., 1923-54; n.d.
    NDRC
  - Duffey, D. K.
  - Duke, B. W.
  - Dukes, T. A.
    - see Keller, Geoffrey
  - Dulles, Allen W.
    - see Ser. III, Citation
  - Du Mond, Jesse W., 1958
  - Dunbar, Charles F.
  - Dunbar, Leslie W., 1957
  - Duncan, Helen L.
  - Dunham, Charles L., 1956; 1968
  - Dunham, E. Alden
    - see Nakicenovic, Slobodan
  - Dunkley, Lilian B.
  - Dunlap, G. W.
    - see Weinberg, Alvin M.
  - Dunlap, R. C., Jr., 1956
  - Dunning, J. R.
    - see Ser. V, Envelope 1b - Dunning, J. R.
  - Dunnington, F. G., 1950-57
    - see also Waters, John A.
  - Durham, Carl T., 1957-58
    Joint Comm. Atomic Energy
  - Durrie, John N., 1949
  - DuShane, Graham, 1956; 1958
  - Dusheck, George, 1954
  - Dushman, Saul, 1944
  - Du Temple, Octave J., 1960-86